Math is the one branch in the world that
is actually perfect. I am 100% sure that
Satoshi actually disappeared because if
he has would have been still around, he
would have spoken and said, "I want this
thing on Bitcoin." As you probably know,
Bonnie, like people are worried about
quantum computers and what they'll do to
uh Bitcoin and to other
cryptocurrencies. So, the first thing is
that what is a quantum computer? If a
quantum computer were built tomorrow, it
could use this sort of maze finding way
to actually break and find keys to
spending all the bitcoin out there,
>> right?
>> That's a problem.
>> But,
>> okay, but
One of the smartest brains in the world
is next to me right now, Ellie Ben
Sassan. He is the co-founder and CEO of
Starkware and the co-founder of Zcash.
You've been waiting for this episode.
Hello, Ellie.
>> Thank you, Bonnie. It's a pleasure to be
here. uh you know very exciting
conference the Binance conference and uh
exciting time to be here
>> for people that might be unfamiliar with
what you do. Why is your mission so
important and why should they care?
>> Blockchain is about integrity. It's
about creating a new layer of trust and
the way Bitcoin did this first is by
basically everyone checking what
everyone else is doing. And that's
great. Bitcoin is great. But there are
two problems with everyone checking what
everyone else is doing. One is that of
privacy because now everyone sees what
you know I'm paying for. That's not
cool. The second problem is scale
because I need my laptop not just for
verifying transactions. I need it also
to do whatever I'm doing. So because of
the privacy and scaling issues, you
know, Bitcoin and Ethereum and other
blockchains are limited at very low
transaction throughput. And Satoshi's
amazing vision is not yet the basis for
a global economy in which companies and
people can just interact. So that's
where I come in. I invented a lot of the
ZK technology that solves both the
privacy and the scalability
problems of blockchain and allows
basically to create a Bitcoin economy on
the same principles as Bitcoin was
founded.
>> I've talked to Adam back and he was
describing this very early days of
Bitcoin that a lot of people were
questioning the trans transparent part.
They're like, well, we love the design,
but what about this? We want privacy.
Take me back to the history. When it
first came out, what was the
conversation like?
>> Well, um, I entered Bitcoin in 2013.
That's when I got redpilled. Uh, I
basically presented my math, the ZK
math. I, you know, co-invented and said,
oh,
>> that was after you learn about Bitcoin.
And then you're like, we need to fix
something. Is that okay? I I was a
professor of computer science and math
at the time, but I was uh working on ZK
technology and I asked to speak at the
Bitcoin conference in 2013 and there I
presented this technology and said look
this is a breakthrough and it solves two
problems. It solves the privacy and the
scalability problem and a lot of you
know Bitcoin OGs at the time said yes we
want this but it takes a while for
Bitcoin to adopt it. Now what I know was
by then Satoshi wasn't talking anymore.
He stopped talking in 2011. He did say
before he stopped talking, oh if ZK was
around, it could really help solve the
anonymity problem of Bitcoin. And then
he disappeared. Then we came in 2013 and
said, look, we have ZK technology that
actually works. And uh so I I am 100%
sure that Satoshi actually disappeared
because if he has would have been still
around, he would have spoken and said,
"I want this thing on Bitcoin." I'm sure
of that.
>> So you don't think the transparency part
is the design? It's more like a
limitation.
>> Satoshi didn't think it's the design. He
saw it as a bug, not as a feature. He
said that I mean even in the white paper
he recommends you know replacing
addresses once in a while in order to
preserve anonymity and in his
correspondence he did say that if you
know ZK was around it could help solve
some of these problems. So yeah I'm sure
that he would have wanted this stuff.
>> For people that are not familiar with
what ZK is maybe like a very simple
explanation.
>> Okay very simple. When you get a bill at
a restaurant, you get this piece of
paper
and it's a bunch of items that says at
the end you should pay whatever $13.50.
What you have is a proof. It is
something that convinces you that you
really have to pay this uh number. And
the way you verify it is by adding up
the sums, you know, computing the VAT,
the tip, whatever. But it is a proof. So
a proof is this piece of information
that convinces you that the right
computation was done. Okay. So ZK proofs
are the same. There are like this
receipt showing that the right thing is
being done. But everything is blanked
out and you still know that the right
thing is being done and the sum you're
going to pay at the restaurant is the
correct one and not 100 times more even
though you don't see anything about it.
So it's a very magical thing. Gives you
integrity without compromising your
privacy. before you, you know, thought
of this, did you come up with different
ways of solving this privacy issue and
then come to ZK in the end or was it a
very aha this was the
>> okay first of all I should say this I
did not invent ZK Z
>> you are the brain behind it
>> well I think it's a little bit like um
you know to take an analogy so you know
if you think about atomic energy there
were the um theoretical breakthroughs of
Einstein and others that showed that you
know you could harness this energy and
then there were others like Oppenheimer
and uh you know Fenoyman and others who
reduced it to practice okay so I come
I'm one of those who are more in the
reducing to practice phase but the
mathematical basics of uh ZK this was
discovered already in 1985 which was way
before I entered the scene so I'm I'm
one of those who helped bring it to the
real world cuz previously it was like
whatever like time travel or cold fusion
or you know quantum computers something
that people are talking about but
doesn't actually work.
>> Maybe I can rephrase my question to have
you explored different huge theories
where you can might be able to fix this
problem.
>> Oh yeah. Yeah. So uh I started as a
mathematician and I did about 20 years
of research that all of it was about or
most of it was about the efficiency of
these proof systems and the very
beautiful math behind them but it's like
very very um complex. Yeah. So, I did a
lot of research there, but then the goal
of that research was to make ZK
practical.
>> And take me back to the moment or like
the period of time when you figured,
hey, this could really help everyday
people.
>> Oh, yeah. So, it was exactly May 2013.
At the time, I was basically showing my
work. So, I was an academic. I was a
professor of of math and computer
science. and I went around mostly
academic places and gave talks saying
hey look uh here's something cool and I
don't know what you can do with it and
the listeners said it's cool we agree we
don't know what to do with it and then I
entered the Bitcoin conference I was
actually there in that area because I
was giving a talk at Stanford and
Berkeley and the Bitcoin conference was
right around was in San Jose so
I came to speak there and I just fell in
love. I like because I realized there,
wow, like this stuff that I've been
looking for
something to do with it. What happened
was like Greg Maxwell and Mike Hearn,
these are like OG core developers of
Bitcoin, they came up to me after I
spoke and they said, "Okay, where's the
code?" And I asked them, "Why do you
need the code?" And they said, "What do
you mean? Here are like five different
things we will do with this code if you
give it to us tomorrow." and I said,
"Okay, wow." Like
this thing clicks. So that was the
moment in time that I fell in love with
Bitcoin and also was the first to
realize that ZK solves both scalability
and privacy for blockchain.
>> So for people that are not familiar,
adding ZK means what? Like means my
Bitcoin transaction.
You can see the transaction but you
don't know who it who it is for or what
are we talking about.
>> Yeah. So today like if I'm going to pay
you in Bitcoin, you'll show me your
address
>> and I will send you something. Now you
can use a browser to see
>> what what I did, how much I have in my
wallet. I can do the same thing with
you. Okay.
>> Imagine that what I do is you you still
give me your public address. What I'm
going to do is I'm going to create
something where everything is encrypted
from the world and even from you and u
so the only thing the world sees is
let's say some hash or some encryption
of the transaction
and then there's this proof this zk
proof that proves that even though
everything is encrypted and you don't
know who is paying whom and how much it
is a true uh payment meaning I own the
funds I'm actually subtracting the funds
You now get the information you need in
order to add funds to your wallet or
whatever. So it all works. You only
learn that you received something and
how much
>> and I cannot track
you know you spending that you cannot
learn anything about me and the world
doesn't even know how much was
transferred.
>> Yeah. Like when I do transactions
sometimes I just come up with just all
new addresses, new wallets just just
because of that.
>> Exactly.
>> But in a world okay when where big
institutions are now onchain and they're
doing transactions, of course they don't
want to be tracked.
>> Exactly.
>> But the regulators want you to be
tracked.
>> Yes. So I want to talk about both
points. Look, so um I run starkware. We
have um you know we built Starknet. Um
my company has about 200 employees and
actually employees are you know can get
part of their salary as paid on Starknet
via like USDC or stable coin
>> and a lot of people uh opt in for this
because we love Starknet
>> and it's like really really easy to use.
Okay. So now my CFO comes to me and says
look this is a problem like if I send
salaries uh you know like I need
>> Exactly. I need to do like a lot of
juggling around.
>> Exactly. And same thing with um
>> service providers, we also pay them. So
exactly what you said is right. Like
once you know DJs be dens, they don't
care that much if whatever the uh small
portion that they're putting aside to
play whatever um with blockchain the
world knows about it. But if you take a
company and you know more and more
companies are are coming to Starknet to
like do stuff um then uh these things
matter. Now you're right that regulators
and also like many jurisdictions
according to their laws in certain cases
information must be revealed. So there
is when I talk about privacy there are
two different set of constraints that
make it hard to solve for on a
blockchain. One is the regulatory set of
constraints and the other is the UX
because often creating these ZK proofs
and privacy just becomes very hard.
Okay. So at Zcash when I co-ounded it
with we went with one pretty extreme you
know full privacy case which um is great
and it was the first um but in terms of
UX and um ability to comply with various
jurisdictions it's a bit more tricky
like there's more uh burden on the users
on whoever is servicing this to do that.
With Starknet, what we're doing is
offering privacy that has much better UX
and more agile when it comes to um
compliance, meaning it's easier for
various entities and providers to get
viewing keys into what happened in cases
they need, which for those who are like,
you know, privacy maxis, they may not
like it. But for those let's say like my
CFO and people who run companies and you
know need to abide by certain laws it is
a must. So it's a different place in the
trade-off. We went for something that
gives you better compliance and better
um UX and that's the position we're
taking with privacy on Starknet.
>> You care about privacy a lot and I want
to know there has to be a story behind
it. Why? Like if I care about something
I'm passionate about something then
there has to be a story behind it. For
me honestly it started with uh so I was
a mathematician
>> and I really believed this math can find
a use case and then when I saw and as I
said I was the first to see and realize
that it solves both scalability and
privacy I said I really want to take
this amazing math
>> and turn it into something real. This
was you know my so I'm not coming to it
from the ideological privacy tech. I
came to it from the I invented this cool
math that I believe can do really good
things in the world and I want to see
people use it and you know every day
every transaction on stark net and on
Zcash uses technology and math that I
actually you know once wrote on a
whiteboard or in a white paper and it's
just such a great feeling that you know
my math and my formulas are now actually
powering the real Bitcoin economy.
I never would have believed that.
>> And people are just following your work
everywhere around the world.
>> Yeah, there are a lot of followers.
Yesterday I just uh had a podcast on
postquantum security. Oh wow. With
professor Scott Aronson, a colleague of
mine who's like the authority on quantum
computation because as you probably
know, Bonnie, like people are worried
about quantum computers and what they'll
do to uh Bitcoin and to other
cryptocurrencies.
>> Would you like to talk about that?
>> I would love to talk about that. So the
first thing is that what is a quantum
computer? It is a machine that uses the
very mysterious laws of uh quantum
mechanics which are mind-blowing and
unbelievable that allow in certain cases
a physical device to sort of try many
things in parallel without quite
committing to any one of them. You're
trying to find a way out of a maze,
right? So you have all of these forks
where you have to take left or right,
left or right. And this happens many
times. So in the quantum world, you know
what we would do if we were walking in
this maze, we would try one, go back,
try another. And a classical computer
works like that. It tries one thing,
tries another, tries a third. In the
quantum world, in some mysterious way,
um sometimes you can have a system where
in parallel all of these paths in the
maze are checked out. And actually for
certain mazes the paths that end at a
dead end die and then the only one that
remains is the correct one. And it's the
universe works in that way and it's like
mind-blowing that like it goes back to
this thing that an electron can be in
like super position or it's not exactly
here or there. So a quantum computer
uses that very mysterious thing in order
to break certain cryptographic systems
and to find keys to uh you know bitcoin
transactions. So that's the threat,
right? If a quantum computer were built
tomorrow, it could use this sort of maze
finding way to actually break and find
keys to spending all the bitcoin out
there.
>> Right?
>> That's a problem. But
>> okay but okay there are other kinds of
mazes
where the quantum you know the the laws
of the universe do not allow you to do
this thing of like it just you know
that's forbidden you cannot take and
check all the paths and then have some
of them the wrong ones die. So there are
kinds of uh cryptographic systems where
you're safe and these are called
postquantum secure systems. So there is
a way to move from the way we own
Bitcoin today to a new way and uh you
know we at Starkware are talking to a
lot of people in trying to advocate for
this and in particular the ZK Starks
that Starknet uses happens to be
postquantum secure. It's one of those
things that remain and you can basically
take all of the blockchain technology
that is, you know, susceptible or could
be broken by a quantum computer and you
can save it using ZK Starks, which is
what we're going to try and, you know,
uh, work on and convince the world to
uh, you know, look at
>> the world has to use it.
>> There are a number of different options,
you know, there are a number of
different ways to have cryptography that
survives a quantum computer. ZK Starks
is one of them. I think it's the best
way for a variety of reasons, but there
are a number of ways and I think we need
all of them.
>> So, is it fair to say that
every day people should not be too
worried yet? Okay. So there is this
report M McKenzie came out this I think
May and then of course quantum computing
is one of the most advanced technology
that we should watch out for but the
adoption was at one that means it's
still so far away from going mainstream
>> are we actually far
>> um so that was the main question I asked
uh professor Aaronson yesterday and we
discussed so um we don't know we don't
know I will say
I'm not I'm an optimist. I think we'll
be fine, but I think we'll be fine. And
this is something that, you know, Scott
said on the interview yesterday. Uh
we'll be fine if we approach it the same
way we approached back in the world this
Y2K bug. So, a lot of computer systems
when they were built, you know, whatever
going and moving to the year 2000 could
have caused like serious problems.
whatever satellites would have crashed
or something but a few years before the
whole computer world said okay this is a
problem let's do all kinds of fixes and
avert it and then what happened was you
know January 1st 2000 came and nothing
happened but nothing happened because we
got prepared my approach to the quantum
threat is similar if we you know bitcoin
other blockchains you know binance a
bunch of uh you know big players in the
field realize this is a threat threat
and we have to act then that's not a
problem. The place where I worry about
Bitcoin is that sometimes you know there
are all these fights about very small
and ridiculous things and then you worry
it's it's like you know if we fight
about those small things then we're just
not going to get enough urgency to fix
the big one which we can.
>> What is the reality now? Like I I hear
people talking about oh yeah all the
companies uh Bitcoin has all the smart
people smartest people and they're
already working on it don't worry. So,
uh, you know, I'm in contact with many
of the core devs and leaders of Bitcoin
and I can tell you I, you know, was
corresponding with many of them just
over the past week and they're all like
on it and saying yes, we, you know,
we're aware on it, we're aware of it,
we're working on it. like one very
famous effort is called BIAP 360 uh
which is a Bitcoin improvement proposal
number 360 which is suggestion is to
replace sort of sus you know the bad uh
cryptography the one that could be
broken by a quantum computer with one
that won't so people are working about
it but you know what I like on Twitter
and other places I am actually trying to
be a little bit more of an alarmist and
the reason is that only if we take a
more alarmist this kind of approach then
w will we avert the problem? If we're
like too complacent and say no don't
worry like it's going to be fine that's
not the right approach. The right
approach is we should be worried let's
fix it. Let's get this thing moving so
that uh it ends up not being a problem.
I'm an optimist. I um you know even
though I'm urging for action and like
you know saying hey let's let's get
work. I would say to those who are you
know asking themselves is Bitcoin safe
enough and so on my answer is yes it is
and you should hold a bit of it not
investment advice but you know it is a
very good asset it's a very important
thing so yes
>> I preach that every single day
>> but would you say no math is perfect
>> no actually I think math is the one
branch in the world that is actually
perfect like meaning if something is
proven and it doesn't have a bug and
most of the core things do not have a
bug then this is more perfect like math
is the most solid and unbreakable kind
of science or art. So math is actually
perfect but what is maybe imperfect is
um our which parts of math do we choose
to apply? So like what is the problem
with the quantum computer? We based all
of the the current um way you own
Bitcoin on certain kind of math. The
quantum computer will break. And this
has been known for like 40 years that
sorry 30 years since 1995.
>> The we knew there was this huge
breakthrough how to use a quantum
computer in order to break cryptography
to factor integers. It's called Shor's
algorithm. So since 1995,
we know that if someone ever builds a
quantum computer, this kind of math is
is not usable. It's not that the math is
broken, it's that um you can't use it
for hiding uh your identity.
>> I love how you explain this.
>> Thank you.
So but back in the days it was a very
small group of people that is aware of
this and now because of all the media
people are like oh
>> well the media is amplifying what is
actually happening at the vanguard of
science you know Google and some other
you know I think IBM and Microsoft they
each one of them have these brilliant
teams of physicists and engineers
building better and better quantum
devices and then the media correctly is
saying hey world like this is actually
coming. Like there there may be a
quantum computer that will then be able
to factor
>> all of the um numbers that are used to
you know protect our Bitcoin. So so like
>> yeah and it's it's good that the media
is doing that like because like yeah we
should get worried and we should act now
>> because most people have no answer to
this question. So I think the most
common answer or explanation I've heard
is oh if that day comes worry about war
don't worry about your bitcoin or worry
about you know the traditional financial
system which is a lot bigger being
attacked but I don't think that is
really answering people's concerns.
Well, I agree. It's not it's not ex So,
you're right that that um even when we
do commerce on the internet,
>> we are using some cryptography that
could be broken by a quantum computer.
>> Yes.
>> But within the conventional like the web
2 world, there's an ongoing effort
Exactly. to you know like this avert
this thing and replace the cryptography
now being used with one that will be
immune to a quantum computer.
Now with Bitcoin the question is will it
be done in time or not? If it's done in
time no problem if it's not done in time
yes there is a problem and let me just
you know expand on that. The reason
people are not yet using these
postquantum signature ways, you know,
for transacting is because they're less
efficient.
>> You know, like takes more time,
the signatures are longer, which means
like blocks are going to be more
clogged. Um, you know, the cost
transaction fees
>> there's an option to use that now. Well,
not on Bitcoin, but I'm I'm saying if
you well, there are some proposals and
if you are to adapt one of them and add
these things, you'll get signatures that
instead of being like this long, they
become much longer and a processing time
in Bitcoin script that is instead of
like this long, it becomes this long,
which means higher transaction fees. So,
so you know, like as long as I don't
have a quantum thread right now, I'd go
for the cheaper, you know, easier
prevailent thing. Another issue is like
most of the hardware and software
wallets today don't support these new
things. So like would be much harder
like I would suddenly need to use my
laptop in order to um transact on
Bitcoin. So that's why you know it makes
sense for folks to um not yet move in
the web 2 world. It's like less of an
issue because people are not as orthodox
about how much computation needs to be
done by the network. Right? If you
suddenly have to do something that takes
10 times more, well, you know, it's a
bummer, but you just do 10 times more
work on Bitcoin. That's a huge problem
because suddenly, you know, blocks fill
up. It's much harder. So, one can do a
bunch of things in order to solve the
problem, but you need more scale and you
need agility and like adopting new
things, which again is like what I think
Starknet does really good. Would you
comment on the recent price action of um
>> what is happening? People are talking
about
>> Zcash being the real Bitcoin. That is
what I'm hearing.
>> I love Zcash. I co-founded it. It's
based on my math. Um I don't think it's,
you know, Bitcoin is the real Bitcoin,
right? And you know the the Zcash is
based on a paper that I co-authored and
it's titled is zero
I think like privacy on Bitcoin. So even
the original suggestion was actually to
bring this to Bitcoin and you know
starknet which is another ZK technology
that gives scale and privacy. I also
want to use it in order to expand the
Bitcoin economy. So I don't think Zcash
replaces Bitcoin. I don't think um
Starknet replaces Bitcoin and I don't
think they should. I think Bitcoin is
great. I would like to see Bitcoin doing
some minor modifications that would
allow it to scale better, you know,
integrate better with something like
Starknet offer privacy. Uh I think that
is the best way for uh Bitcoin. But uh I
certainly you know I didn't create Zcash
in order to replace Bitcoin. No,
>> the original mission was not.
>> No, it was well the original mission was
as scientists to say, "Hey, Bitcoin,
here's something you Bitcoin like we
Bitcoin can do and add privacy." But
then we realized that like it will take
a very long time and indeed you know we
published that paper in 2014. So that
was 12 years ago almost well 11 years
ago and uh we wanted as as I told you I
came into this space as an entrepreneur
because I wanted my to be you know
out there and usable. I don't want to
wait 50 years and then hear that it was
implemented on Bitcoin. I mean so I want
to do it wherever I can. Um but I think
the best thing is like for Bitcoin to
add privacy and scale in a variety of
very simple ways. The simplest is to um
adopt this thing called opcat which is
nine lines of code that Satoshi
introduced and then basically Bitcoin
automatically has all the privacy and
all the scale it needs under Bitcoin
principles by basically having Starknet
as its financialization layer. So like
Bitcoin can stay the great Bitcoin it is
and have this huge expansion by adding
nine lines of code and making it greater
than ever.
>> The reason why I hesitated a little bit
earlier about how Zcash is the real
Bitcoin is because I saw that comment in
like the altcoins forums and you know
how people that the Bitcoin believers
are a little sensitive when it comes to
this. But what I'm hearing now is this
is all benefiting the Bitcoin ecosystem.
>> In my view it is. Yes.
>> But do you get any
other type of opinion push backs?
>> Of course you get like there are a lot
of people ultra maxis of Bitcoin which
to them anything you know it's almost
this religious thing which basically
says Bitcoin in its current form with no
change is like the word of God and
cannot be improved upon. and uh any sort
of thing that someone might want to
offer to it the you should say no this
is you know this is not Bitcoin and so
it's just uh
it's you know shitcoin it's bad it's a
scam people whatever
I strongly disagree with that I think
technology moves on I think Bitcoin can
you know cautiously add some things that
will improve it I think it can be
improved on without you know ru ruining
any of the things that make it so great.
>> Are you working on anything that is very
exciting that you can share with people?
>> I work only uh first of all I do very
little work right now. I get too much
credit for what my amazing team is
working on. So uh I mostly speak and uh
try to give inspiration but my team is
working I would say we only work on
extremely exciting stuff. So some of the
stuff we are working on um is adding
things like privacy
um in a usable good UX way trying to
connect Starknet to Bitcoin and to Zcash
increasing scale um allowing the Bitcoin
economy to expand. Let me just mention
one thing because it's very concrete and
it's a call to action to anyone out
there. Okay, it goes like this. Bitcoin
right now is, you know, the greatest
asset out there as out there as a store
of value, but people are just holding
it. I think that a lot of people who
hold it would like to see an economy
that is based on Bitcoin as an asset
grow and expand, but it has to be very
much the in the Bitcoin spirit, which
means you own your life. You own your
coins. You don't transfer custody to
anyone. You have good UX. You have a
mature technology. Okay? All of that
exists today on Startet. So, here's how
you can participate. Today you can take
Bitcoin and you can stake it on Startet
which is a decentralized layer 2 for
Bitcoin and you will earn yield by doing
so. There's already upwards of I think
there's about 1,800 Bitcoin already
staked and generating about 2 to 4% of
yield right now. So now once you stake
the yield that you get is in the STRK
token which is the token for operating
start. Now as the economy expands and
more economic activity on Bitcoin
happens, if you take the STRK that you
received and you stake that, you will
receive further yield and you will see
this whole uh economy which is the
Bitcoin economy expanding. So there's a
way for you to very safely hold your
Bitcoin but still support the expansion
of the Bitcoin economy on Starknet. So
you can just go and look for Starknet
BTC staking and you know follow from
there.
>> One last question about the staking. Are
companies staking their Bitcoin?
>> Yes.
>> With you?
>> Because this is my question. If I'm a
retail investor that stakes a couple of
Bitcoin, I am probably okay with, you
know, the risk I'm taking. But if you
we're talking about strategy with 650k
Bitcoin, now what?
>> Well, strategy isn't yet um staying
>> in at a later stage, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I think at a later
stage, first of all, I think a lot of
the digital asset treasury companies
dealing with Bitcoin, you know, I speak
to many of the leaders of them, they are
looking for ways to generate yield in a
safe way. and they also u you know agree
with my vision that you want a Bitcoin
economy. Yeah.
>> Okay. So um I think I'm very optimistic
that we'll see more and more of these
companies of these uh digital asset you
know these debts um seeking yield and
participating in the Bitcoin economy on
Starknet and I think it's a very safe
way and a very good way to you know
expand the Bitcoin mission and make
Bitcoin this this not just this asset
that is being hodled by very few but the
basis for a new economy in which you
know you and I own our lives in a true
sense like you know we never have to
call customer service. Uh we really own
our life.
>> This is this is what happened uh to me
two days ago. I had a lady on an app uh
she's a masseuse. She came over to my
hotel room. I was very tired from a
flight. Now when she before she left,
she said, "Please give me good rating."
And I was like, "Oh, sure. How do I do
this?" And this lady has no clue which
app it is, where her service is being
advertised. And that got me thinking
about privacy and what blockchain can
really do for people, but I don't have a
very definite answer yet.
>> Yes.
>> Do you have any
maybe like a vision of
>> I have a vision.
>> Okay.
>> The vision is it's it's exactly this
like the way I see Stark is a place
where you own your life. What does that
mean? Well, first of all, what there are
some things you never need to do. As I
said, you never need, you know, your
transactions are never blocked and you
never need to call, you know, some
customer service to say, I want to move
funds from here to there. You own your
life. The second thing about you owning
your life means that all of the
transactions that you do, so much of
what we do today is on the digital in
the digital world right now, it is it is
custodied with others. So like think
about our credit history. Who holds it
and where do we get it from? It's not
with us, you know, and then our social
media interactions, our profile, this is
monetized ando held in custody by
others. So I see my vision is this thing
I call it the integrity web where it's
like a layer on top of the worldwide web
where your reputation your history your
actions you know the reviews you give um
your credit history is first of all
privately held with you and only with
you and you choose you know whom to
share it with you can monetize it u you
know you can prove and assert your
integrity u using ZK K and math and
stuff like that. You don't need to go to
a credit rating agency and say, "Oh,
please, you know, give me a letter that
shows whatever I paid my debts." You can
do it by your own. And the technology
exists today. And and this is literally,
you know, if you go to the Starkware
page and you look at mission and vision,
the vision is exactly what I'm, you
know, what we're ending with here. It's
the integrity web where you and I own
our lives. And it's not the um
centralized companies that we need to go
and ask for letters that prove our
integrity. We assert it by ourselves.
>> I love that this whole interview is like
a full circle. And that was a perfect
ending. I feel very zen right now.
Thank you, Ellie. Please come back soon
and come to Taiwan.
>> I will.
>> Yes. Yes. We we would love to have you
here. Thank you.
>> Okay. Thank you.